23 chapter 24 Of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is In the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 24 The Lady Anne, or a Runaway
Horse Early in the spring, Lord and part of his family went up to London, and took
York with them. I and Ginger and some other horses were left at home for use,
and the Headroom was left in charge. The Lady Harriet, who remained at
the hall, was a great invalid, and never went out in the carriage, and the Lady
Anne preferred riding on horseback with her brother or cousins. She was a perfect
horsewoman, and as gay and gentle as she was beautiful. She chose me for her horse,
and named me “Black Auster”. I enjoyed these rides very much
in the clear cold air, sometimes with Ginger, sometimes with
Lizzy This Lizzy was a bright baymare almost thoroughbred, and a great favorite
with a gentleman on account of her fine action and lively spirit; but Ginger, who
knew more of her than I did, told me she was rather
nervous. There was a gentleman of the name of blany staying at the hall; he
always rode Lizzy and praised her so much that one day Lady Anne ordered the
side saddle to be put on her, and the other saddle on me. When we came to the
door the gentleman seemed seemed very uneasy. “How is this?” he said. “Are you tired
of your good Black AER Oh no no, not at all,” she replied, “but
I'm amiable enough to let you ride him for once, and I will try your charming
Lizzy You must confess that in size and appearance she is far more like a lady's
horse than my own favorite.” “Do let me advise you not to
mount her,” he said; “she is a charming creature, but she is too nervous for a
lady. I assure you, she is not per perfectly safe; let me beg you to have the saddles
changed.” “My dear cousin,” said Lady Anne, laughing, “pray do not trouble your good
careful head about me. I have been a horsewoman ever since I was a baby, and I
have followed the hounds a great many times, though I know you do not approve
of ladies hunting; but still that is the fact, and I intend to try this Lizzy that
you gentlemen are all so fond of; so please help me to mount, like a good
friend as you are.” There was no more to be said; he placed
her carefully on the saddle, looked to the bit and curb, gave the rins gently
into her hand, and then mounted me. Just as we were moving off a footman
came out with a slip of paper and message from the Lady Harriet. “Would they
ask this question for her at Dr. Ashley's, and bring the
answer?” The village was about a mile off, and the doctor's house was the last in
it. We went along gay enough till we came to his gate. There was a short drive up
to the house between tall evergreens Blan all lighted at the gate,
and was going to open it for Lady Anne, but she said, “I will wait for you here,
and you can hang aer's rain on the gate.” He looked at her doubtfully. “I will
not be 5 minutes,” he said. “Oh, do not hurry yourself; Lizzie and I shall not run away
from you.” He hung my rain on one of the iron spikes, and was soon hidden among the
trees Lizzy was standing by the side of the
road a few paces off, with her back to me.
My young mistress was sitting easily with a loose rain humming a little song.
I listened to my rider's footsteps until they reached the house, and heard him knock at the
door. There was a meadow on the opposite side of the road, the gate of which stood
open; just then some cart horses and several young colts came trotting out in
a very disorderly manner, while a boy behind was cracking a great
whip. The colts were wild and frolicsome, and one of them bolted across the road
and blundered up against Liz's hind legs, and whether it was the stupid cult or
the loud cracking of the whip, or both together, I cannot say, but she gave a
violent kick, and dashed off into a head long gallop. It was so sudden that Lady
Anne was nearly unseated, but she soon recovered herself. I gave a loud, shrill nay for
help; again and again I N pouring the ground impatiently, and tossing my head
to get the rain loose. I had not long to wait. Blantyre came running to the gate;
he looked anxiously about, and just caught sight of the flying figure, now far away on the
road. In an instant he sprang to the saddle. I needed no whip, no spur, for I
was as eager as my rider; he saw it, and giving me a free reain and leaning a
little forward, we dashed after them. For about a mile and a half the
road ran straight, and then bent to the right, after which it divided into two
roads. Long before we came to the bend she was out of sight. Which way had she
turned? A woman was standing at her garden gate, shading her eyes with her
hand, and looking eagerly up the road.
Scarcely drawing the rain blant shouted, “Which way?” “To the right!” cried the woman,
pointing with her hand, and away we went up the right hand road; then for a moment
we caught sight of her; another bend and she was hidden again. Several times we caught glimpses,
and then lost them. We scarcely seemed to gain ground upon them at
all. An old Road mender was standing near a heap of stones, his shovel dropped and his hands
raised. As we came near he made a sign to speak blanty drew the rain a little. “To
the common do the common, sir; she has turned off there.” I knew this common very well; it
was for the most part very uneven ground, covered with heather and dark green Furs
bushes, with here and there a scrubby old Thorn Tree there were also open spaces
of fine short grass, with ant hills and mol turns everywhere; the worst place I
ever knew for a headlong gallop. We had hardly turned onto the
common, when we caught sight again of the green habit flying on before us. My
lady's hat was gone, and her long brown hair was streaming behind her. Her head
and body were thrown back, as if she were pulling with all her remaining strength,
and as if that strength were nearly exhausted. It was clear that the
roughness of the ground had very much lessened lizz's speed, and there seemed a
chance that we might overtake her. While we were on the high road Blan
had given me my head; but now, with a light hand and a practiced eye, he guided
me over the ground in such a masterly manner that my pace was scarcely
slackened, and we were decidedly G in on them. About halfway across the heath
there had been a wide Dyke recently cut, and the earth from the cutting was cast
up roughly on the other side. Surely this would stop them! But no; with scarcely a
pause Lizzy took the leap, stumbled among the rough clouds and fell blanty groaned,
“Now AER do your best!” He gave me a steady rain I gathered
myself well together and with one determined leap cleared both Dyke and
bank. Motionless among the heather, with her face to the earth, lay my poor young
mistress blanty kneeled down and called her name: there was no
sound. Gently he turned her face upward: it was ghastly white and the eyes were
closed. “Annie, dear Annie, do speak!” But there was no
answer. He unbuttoned her habit, loosened her collar, felt her hands and wrist, then
started up and looked wildly round him for help. At no great distance there were two
men cutting turf, who, seeing Lizzy running wild without a rider, had left
their work to catch her bl's Halo soon brought them to the spot. The foremost
man seemed much troubled at the sight, and asked what he could do. “Can you
ride?” “Well, sir, I be ain't much of a horseman, but I'd risk my neck for the
Lady Anne; she was UNC common good to my wife in the
winter.” “Then mount this horse, my friend— —your neck will be quite safe— —and ride to
the doctors and ask him to come instantly; then onto the hall; tell them
all that you know, and bid them send me the carriage, with Lady Anne's maid and
help. I shall stay here.” “All right, sir, I'll do my best, and I
pray God the dear young lady may open her eyes soon.” Then, seeing the other man, he called
out, “Here, Joe, run for some water, and tell
my M to come as quick as she can to the Lady
Anne.” He then somehow scrambled into the saddle, and with a G up” and a clap on my
sides with both his legs, he started on his journey, making a little circuit to avoid the
Dyke He had no whip, which seemed to trouble him; but my pace soon cured that
difficulty, and he found the best thing he could do was to stick to the saddle
and hold me in, which he did manfully. I shook him as little as I
could help, but once or twice on the rough ground he called out, “Steady whoa
Steady!” On the high road we were all right; and at the doctors and the hall he
did his errand like a good man and true.
They asked him in to take a drop of something. “No, no,” he said; “I'll be back to
him again by a shortcut through the fields, and be there aford the
carriage.” There was a great deal of hurry and excitement after the news became
known. I was just turned into my box; the saddle and Bridal were taken off, and the
cloth thrown over me. Ginger was saddled and sent off in
great haste for Lord George, and I soon heard the carriage roll out of the
yard. It seemed a long time before Ginger came back, and before we were left alone;
and then she told me all that she had seen. “I can't tell much,” she said. “We went
to Gallup nearly all the way, and got there just as the doctor rode up. There
was a woman sitting on the ground with a lady's head in her lap. The doctor poured
something into her mouth, but all that I heard was, 'She is not dead.' Then I was led
off by a man to a little distance. After a while she was taken to the carriage,
and we came home together. I heard my master say to a gentleman who stopped
him to inquire, that he hoped no bones were broken, but that she had not spoken
yet.” When Lord George took Ginger for hunting, York shook his head; he said it
ought to be a steady hand to train a horse for the first season, and not a
random rider like the Lord George. Ginger used to like it very much, but sometimes
when she came back I could see that she had been very much strained, and now and
then she gave a short cough. She had too much spirit to complain, but I could not
help feeling anxious about her. Two days after the accident blanty
paid me a visit; he patted me and praised me very much; he told Lord George that he
was sure the horse knew of Annie's danger as well as he did. “I could not
have held him in if I would,” said he, “she ought never to ride any other
horse.” I found by their conversation that my young mistress was now out of danger,
and would soon be able to ride again.
This was good news to me and I looked forward to a happy life end of chapter